Dublin, Ireland | +353 833 78 72 29 | imcvarma@gmail.com | www.mahendra.design

Mahendra Indukuri

ABOUT ME

Design graduate and cognitive science researcher with over 18 months of experience working in UI/UX design roles. Expertise in developing interactive prototypes and style sheets using various tools like **Sketch, Adobe XD, Adobe CC and Zeplin**. My background and aptitude in design, engineering and psychology help me tackle diverse problems in the domain of user experience and digital product design.

EXPERIENCE

Optum (UnitedHealth Group) — UX Design Intern

JUNE 2020 - AUGUST 2020, DUBLIN

- "Exceeded Expectations" in contributions towards research, analysis and design according to end of term review.
- Conducted interviews and surveys to answer key questions relating to remote work and the future of work at Optum.
- Designed and tested an interface to address FOMO and disconnect that remote worker's experience.

Silverlabs India (<u>rizzle.tv</u>) – *UI/UX Designer*

FEBRUARY 2019 - JULY 2019, HYDERABAD

Worked on Rumbl (currently renamed Rizzle) application, Rumbl is a vlogging and social video creation app. It was conceived, designed and developed from scratch during my tenure at the organisation as the lead designer. (visit: rizzle.tv)

- Created user personas and analysed competing apps to find a market gap for a new photo/video mobile app.
- Conducted user interviews and created multiple iterations for A/B testing based on stakeholder feedback.
- Built wireframes, information architecture and task flow for multiple initial versions of the app.
- Created UI mockups including Iconography using Sketch/Adobe XD for both iOS and Android apps.
- Collaborated with UI devs to create micro-interactions, video player interactivity and animations in the app.
- Created Zeplin and additional documentation for UI devs regarding colour codes, aspect ratio, styling, resolutions.

WitCurve Tech. – Product Designer

JULY 2018 - JANUARY 2019, HYDERABAD

WitCurve's products include web application that functions as an information management tool for K-12 educational institutions and a mobile application for parents and teachers for viewing performance-related data. (visit: witcurve.com)

- Translated research findings into wireframes and presented multiple iterations low-fidelity mockups to stakeholders.
- Designed the UI/UX for Ionic 3 (hybrid iOS and Android app) based mobile application from scratch, deliverables included high fidelity mockups, style guides using Zeplin, Iconography and Information Architecture of the app.
- Designed UI for a web-based ERP tool based on Angular material framework, deliverables included iconography, high fidelity mockups, information architecture, documentation and animations for various micro-interactions.
- Developed front-end (HTML/CSS/AngularJS) for UI intensive data visualisation features.

Societe Generale Global Solutions Center — Summer Internship (UI/UX Design)

MAY 2017 - JULY 2017, BANGALORE

Worked on an application related to compliance in financial product trading.

- Designed a web-based application for viewing & editing FPML (Financial Product Markup Language).
- Designed and developed multiple data tables using Angular & material UI frameworks.

EDUCATION

University College Dublin – MSc. Cognitive Science

SEPTEMBER 2019 - AUGUST 2020, DUBLIN.

Graduated from UCD with a masters degree in cognitive science focusing in psychology, philosophy of mind, computational modelling, neuropsychology and other contemporary approaches to cognitive science. Course work includes substantial first-hand research and literature research. Thesis project in the domain of human learning mentioned below.

Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati — Bachelor of Design

JULY 2014 - MAY 2018, GUWAHATI.

Graduated from IIT Guwahati with a bachelor's degree in Design focusing on new media and interaction design. Coursework included project-based courses in graphic design, ergonomics, product design, interaction design and usability engineering.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Towards a Unified Theory of Chunking — School of Computer Science, University College Dublin

Developed a new theoretical approach for understanding the phenomenon of chunking based on an embodied approach to cognition and memory. Research in this domain has seminal implications for future interfaces specifically neural interfaces.

Storytelling in Virtual Reality — Media Lab, Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati

Worked on Virtual Reality (VR) and the future of storytelling in VR, explored concepts such as hypermontage and gaze-based interactivity through an interactive prototype for google cardboard developed using unity.